[
  {
    "id": 1,
    "question": "A person who believes that laws and governments are not necessary is known as -",
    "options": ["a militant", "a terrorist", "an anarchist", "an extremist"],
    "answer": "an anarchist"
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "question": "He went to ___ hospital because he had ___ heart attack. Use article in the gap-",
    "options": ["no article, an", "a, an", "no article, a", "the, no article"],
    "answer": "no article, a"
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "question": "The word 'florid' indicates--",
    "options": ["flower", "flour", "foliage", "floor"],
    "answer": "flower"
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "question": "Complete the following sentence :'Had I known you were waiting outside, I -",
    "options": [
      "had invited you to come in",
      "would invite you to come in",
      "would be inviting you to come in",
      "would have invited you to come in"
    ],
    "answer": "would have invited you to come in"
  },
  {
    "id": 5,
    "question": "Cricket is a kind of play. It is also a kind of --",
    "options": ["food", "bird", "flower", "insect"],
    "answer": "insect"
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "question": "A soporific speech is likely to --",
    "options": [
      "be incomprehensible",
      "appeal primarily to emotions",
      "put one to sleep",
      "stimulate action"
    ],
    "answer": "put one to sleep"
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "question": "Select the word with right spelling -",
    "options": [
      "Schizophrenia",
      "Seizophrania",
      "Scizophrenia",
      "Schizophrania"
    ],
    "answer": "Schizophrenia"
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "question": "Love for the whole world is called ?",
    "options": ["misogyny", "misanthropy", "philanthropy", "benevolence"],
    "answer": "philanthropy"
  },
  {
    "id": 9,
    "question": "When we want to mean a government by the richest class we use the term",
    "options": ["Oligarchy", "Cryptocracy", "Aristocracy", "Plutocracy"],
    "answer": "Plutocracy"
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "question": "Hospitals ___ the sick",
    "options": ["operate", "admit", "nurse", "treat"],
    "answer": "treat"
  },
  {
    "id": 11,
    "question": "The warning of the authority falls on deaf ears. Here warning does the function of -",
    "options": ["adverb", "adjective", "verb", "noun"],
    "answer": "noun"
  },
  {
    "id": 12,
    "question": "Identify the correct passive form of the sentence below:\n\n'Do you know them?",
    "options": [
      "Are they known by you?",
      "Are they known to you?",
      "Ate they known with you?",
      "Would they be known by you?"
    ],
    "answer": "Are they known to you?"
  },
  {
    "id": 13,
    "question": "'Panacea' means-",
    "options": ["pancreatic", "Cure all", "widespread disease", "gland"],
    "answer": "Cure all"
  },
  {
    "id": 14,
    "question": "What is the plural number of 'ovum' -",
    "options": ["ovams", "ovumes", "ova", "ovums"],
    "answer": "ova"
  },
  {
    "id": 15,
    "question": "কোন শব্দযুগলটি ভিন্ন?",
    "options": [
      "False, True",
      "Sharp, Blunt",
      "Abundance, Scarcity",
      "Love, affection"
    ],
    "answer": "Love, affection"
  },
  {
    "id": 16,
    "question": "'A Christams Carol' is a ___ by Charles Dickens.",
    "options": ["ballad", "sketch story", "historical novel", "Short Novel"],
    "answer": "Short Novel"
  },
  {
    "id": 17,
    "question": "'There was a small reception following the wedding'. The word 'following' in the sentence above is a/an -",
    "options": ["adjective", "adverb", "Preposition", "noun"],
    "answer": "Preposition"
  },
  {
    "id": 18,
    "question": "Which of the following words has been formed with a prefix?",
    "options": ["authentic", "amoral", "amnesia", "aspersions"],
    "answer": "amoral"
  },
  {
    "id": 19,
    "question": "লেফটেন্যান্ট জেনারেল শব্দের সঠিক ইংরেজি বানান কোনটি?",
    "options": ["Lieutenant", "Leaftenant", "Leiftenant", "Lieaflenant"],
    "answer": "Lieutenant"
  },
  {
    "id": 20,
    "question": "'To be, or not to be - that is the question,'-- is a famous soliloquy from --",
    "options": ["Hamlet", "Macbeth", "King Lear", "Othello"],
    "answer": "Hamlet"
  },
  {
    "id": 21,
    "question": "'Geriatrics' is the branch of medicine concerned with the diseases and care of --",
    "options": ["old women", "newly-weds", "newborn babies", "old people"],
    "answer": "old people"
  },
  {
    "id": 22,
    "question": "নিচের উপমাটি পূর্ণকারী শব্দ কোনটি ?",
    "options": ["Flower", "Tree", "Twig", "Branch"],
    "answer": "Twig"
  },
  {
    "id": 23,
    "question": "'Hand out' এর শুদ্ধ বাংলা পরিভাষা হচ্ছে ?",
    "options": ["হস্ত পত্র", "প্রচার পত্র", "জ্ঞাপনপত্র", "তথ্য পত্র"],
    "answer": "জ্ঞাপনপত্র"
  }
]
